MICHAEL MILROY

Software Developer

Process Improvement Specialist

Agile Coach

CONTACT

- **(765)** 977-6349
- michaeldmilroy@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/mdmilroy

Focused Veteran and college graduate with a Bachelor of Science (B.S.) in Psychology, and 10 years of professional work experience. Aiming to leverage academic experience with proven knowledge of process improvement, crossfunctional team building, development, and statistical process control to successfully contribute to an amazing team.

EXPERIENCE

Indiana Bureau of Motor Vehicles

January 2019 – Present

Intake Lead • Process Improvement • Project Management

- Current member of the leadership team coordinating and executing the strategic reopening of the agency after state-wide shutdown in response to COVID-19.
- Provide real-time data analytics to Executives in making data-informed decisions.
- Lead Six Sigma Black Belt initiative reducing output of development teams by over 30% in three months

United States Marine Corps

June 2010 - June 2015

Signals Intelligence Collection Operator/Analyst

- Flew 470 combat hours on over enemy held positions, providing real-time data collection and intelligence analysis, in direct support of Special Operations Forces.
- Developed standard protocol for documenting, scanning, and transferring classified equipment which was later adopted by the organization's management.

EDUCATION

Eleven Fifty Academy

February – July 2020

Software Developer

- Web design with HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap
- Web application development in .Net Framework and C#
- RESTful APIs, n-tier architecture, and MVC integration using Entity Framework.
- Integration with SQL Server

Purdue University

August 2017 – December 2018

B.S. Psychology

- Organizational Psych
- Statistical Processes
- Research lab assistant

CERTIFICATIONS

- Certified Six Sigma Black Belt
- SAFe Program Consultant 5.0
- Certified Scrum Master
- Certified Associate in Project Management (CAPM)
- Python Data Analyst (DataCamp)